Danielle Swank

4685 Hwy 111 North, Cookeville, TN 38506

931-284-9478

danielle@danielleswank.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Accomplished UX director with an 9-year career in web development and graphic design. Demonstrated success in leading \$300K+ design / development projects from initial concept stage to final production operations, directing large multi-disciplinary teams, and communicating with clients and vendors.

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

FreeFlow Labs, Co-Founder / Designer

2011 - Present

http://freeflow.io Co-Founded a web startup to provide accurate content recommendations for social news. The FreeFlow app is a visual social news reader that pulls in a users social streams, extracts content from shared links.

ARS Interactive, UX / Creative Director

2009 - Present

http://thinkars.com In charge of a multi-disciplinary team of 9 designers and developers. Directly participated in bringing in over \$1M of business this year. Responsible for the architecture and front-end development of a \$300K+ custom CMS for Sears. Designed a \$100K+ eCommerce content web application for Proctor and Gamble. Increased Sears.com toy vertical "visits to orders" metric by 63%. Smoothly launched a redesign of http://www.kenmore.com during the middle of the 2009 holiday season. Developed http://shop.pbskids.org and http://shop.pbski

Ticketmaster – Echo Music / Ticketmaster, UX Developer

2008

Updated the user interface of Echo's web application platform and did rapid prototyping of new projects.

Ciphertek LLC, Designer / Front-End Developer

2007

Web site design and front end development.

Tri State Distribution, Graphic Designer / Sales and Marketing Manager

2005 - 2007

Designed and marketed new products. Managed a national sales team focusing on B to B and Dept. Of Defense.

Ornament Boutique, Founder

2002 - 2005

Founded a gift-ware company specializing in hand-blown glass. Designed all products and marketing materials, and developed a strong-selling line of off-season ornaments. Increased sales volume by 400% in 4 years.

Selected Freelance Work

2002 - Present

Association of Visual Arts Instructor – Taught classes in wordpress, web design, and social media. Gemini Command – Node Knockout entry, placed in the top 10 for design and top 25 overall of ~300 teams. Chattablocks.com – Government and community information web portal for Chattanooga, TN.

Ephemera Book – 3-year photography project documenting the work of K. Yerizarian, New York, NY.

Makom Shalom Ark of the Torah Bronze – Bronze sculpture for Makom Shalom Synagogue in Chicago, IL.

TNIADA – Won a 2008 business partner award for the Tennessee Independent Auto Dealers Association website.

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING & EDUCATION

University of Tennessee, Fine Art

1998 - 2002

Lifetime member of the Golden Key National Honor Society